Chandangad
- Porter ! - Yes ?
To the Thakur 's Mansion
You seem new around here . Don 't you know ?
All the Thakur 's have been got rid of
You shouldn 't venture out there alone
But I must
- I reached in the nick of time . - Dr. Pandey , you still in this town ?
Come , I 've to collect you .
- Porter ! - Yes , sir ?
Keep the luggage in the buggy
- Please ... - Let 's go
So , the Mansion is a haunted house now
Time takes its toll
I too feel scared to approach it . But I can 't leave my job either
In fact , there 's no need of a doctor there at all
Nobody dies of any illness there . He 's murdered !
Your Uncle nearly met with the same fate , but I reached there
Tried my best to take him to a hospital but he died in route
Looks as though this isn 't a man 's job
That 's what bugs me
- What the hell is going on ? - It 's natural
It 's 20 years now since your Grandpa was murdered
Then , your father . What can one say ?
Your Uncle firmly believed that the family was cursed
He had even declared a reward to catch the murderer
Even then , nothing happened . Even the police are stumped
And what if something happens to me ?
Well , according to the will I should inherit the estate
But a few days before , or after your Uncle 's death ...
Mr. Mohan came here to ask for his share of the estate
Who 's he ?
The same man whose father quarreled with your Grandpa
But that quarrel wasn 't over the estate . It was a different issue
Anyway , leave all this . - What does Mohan do here ?
That 's a riddle too . Actually , something 's wrong with his legs
But , with the support of a crutch he 's always roaming around
Seeing all this , I wasn 't keen for you to come back from London
Honestly , your life 's in danger
The Mansion 's old servant . Laxman
I understand
I understand , sir
I live across the swamp . If you need me , call me over
Actually ... Laxman ! You must 've done what I had told you to do
Okay then , Kumar . I 've some very important job to do
- Goodnight . - Goodnight .
See you ...
Come , sir
The whole staff , servants of this Mansion ran off
I would 've gone too , but since you were to come , I remained here
Again the same room . A landlord ...
All the landlords ... they all stayed in this room
That door ...
It opens ... straight towards the swamp
The same jingling of the anklets ...
And all the landlords were murdered
Laxman ...
I 'll stay in this room
In this room ?
Fine
In the daylight this city seems to be even more beautiful
There 's spring everywhere
" My beautiful childhood dreams twinkle in my eyes "
" When the clouds loom overhead , they pierce my heart "
" My lonely heart fears that the time is passing by "
" How to pass these confused times ... How I wish I was a child again ! "
" My lovely childhood dreams sway in my eyes like blossom "
" When the cuckoo sings from afar why does my heart miss a beat ? "
" I die of shyness , when the bee buzzes over a flower "
" The breeze strings my heart . How I wish , I could stop it "
" My lovely childhood dreams sway in my eyes like blossom "
A white hunter , in the village , eh ?
He shoots birds ... that too with a gun !
Even then , he missed the target !
Shall I kill a few ?
Birds , I mean
Mr. Bird-shooter , if you 're so keen to hunt , then go shoot a tiger
The sound of your gun scared my goats to a stampede
Now who 'll go after them and bring them back home ?
I 'm talking to you . Did you hear me or not ?
Go and gather my goats !
No answer . He doesn 't know Hindi
Well sir , how do you do ? You 're not mental , are you ?
Still quiet ? This man isn 't deaf , is he ?
Right . I am Radha . I 'll try and make him understand
Look . Those goats there ... they are mine . Mine
Because of the noise from your gun ... Noise ... they got scared
and ran helter-skelter here and there
Go collect them and bring them to me . Okay
Now , go and get them
He doesn 't even bat an eyelid . May be he 's blind too
Oh , I see . Can 't hear , can 't see
then , why is he shooting ?
Even if a few birds die , he can surely pick them ...
Great !
Run Radha ... if he can see you , he 'll be after you
Hey , that 's blood . I 'm very sorry
One who can bear to watch fish writhe out of water
Why is he so upset seeing a little blood ?
Corpses don 't move me at all , but ...
It 's not necessary that one who possesses anklets is the killer
And it isn 't necessary that a man carry them around without a reason
If you take the trouble to come to my place at night
you 'll get an answer to this query too
Kumar is still at the Mansion . I don 't think he 'll come now
I think so too . This time we 're dealing with a smart alec
But at times , too much smartness proves dangerous too
Master !
What 's that noise ?
Nobody can survive here . Nobody !
It 's cast ...
It 's been cast ...
The murderous evil eye of
has been cast on a member of this family , yet again
- Revenge ! - Revenge ?
- Revenge ... - What revenge ?
Laxman ! You want to hide something , eh ?
20 years ago , when your Grandpa became the Lord of the Manor
he played games with the women of this village , married or unmarried
But this girl ran away . The daughter of the headman of Rampur
ran away before he could rape her
No ! Leave me alone . Let me go ! No ! No !
From that night a fearsome ghost was born in this village
That night , when the headman came to the Mansion at night
and begged for his daughter 's honor
your Grandpa had him whipped mercilessly
Got him thrown away ...
But why was this picture hung here ?
It was hung ...
It was hung here so that no man from the family
should ever repeat the blunder
Everybody knows everything about this Mansion in detail
But nobody knows anything about the killer !
No , they don 't
Uncle , no doubt you 're the village medic
but you 're always coughing . Thank God , I don 't fall sick
And even if I do , I won 't get treated from you !
My dear , this cough is due to my old age . It won 't go now
You and your cat are both alike . You can 't know your illness
And she doesn 't know her own people !
Put your whiskers down , else , no food !
Coming ... wherever I turn , noise all around
Silly girl
- It 's the same ghost - What ?
That crying ... I 'm scared that it may not
take my life ? - It 's possible . Quite possible
My thoughts exactly . I can tackle one ghost
But here there are ghosts all over . One in the house
One in the village . And one in the swamp too !
Who are you ?
So ! You roam around here to kill all the Landlords , eh ?
No ... I 've just come here . I 'm a detective . A spy
And about the killer , I 've come to catch him and claim the reward
Good you came , the killer can 't be caught at all
How can he be ? Here , people catch hold of the detective instead !
Could the real murderer be on guard ahead ?
I say ... The road is dangerous
Road is dangerous indeed ! Hey , what 's this ?
I say ... help ! Can you hear me ? Save me
- I told you it was dangerous - Save me !
Don 't get panicky
I told you the road was dangerous
- Save me , oh please ! - Don 't be scared . Be brave
- Oh God , I 'll die now - Don 't go there . Try to catch this
- Go on , try - A bit lower
Catch it ... come on .
- Okay ? - Yes
I 'm letting it go now . Right . I 've let it go
Stretch your foot and put it there
- Where ? - Here , over here
The ground is hard here . Catch hold of me . Come on , now
- You are very lucky , sir - Thank you . You saved my life
That 's my profession . I 'm the village physician , Ramlal
- And I 'm Gopichand , a detective - Where were you heading ?
- I 've forgotten - Was it the Manor ?
Yes ... the Manor
Then follow this road - No danger there , is there ?
No
1 , 2 , 3 , 4 , 5 , 6 , 7 , 8 , 9 , 10 ...
11 , 12 , 13 , 14 , 15 , 16 , 17 , 18 , 19 , 20 ...
I read about your father in my Uncle 's diary
- He was a renowned detective - Yes
And what about you ?
I 'm a great detective too , that 's why I survived the swamp ordeal
Any other man in my place , would be with the Lord now !
I think , you will catch the killer soon
I 'm in no hurry at all
If you make arrangements for my stay here , since I 'm broke
then I 'll catch the killer , even after he kills you !
Then you must certainly stay here ! Laxman ...
- Who 's this Laxman ? - My servant . Why ?
Five years ago , a dacoit named Laxman had escaped from jail
- This Laxman isn 't that same ... - Master ?
Laxman , this detective will stay here .
See to all the arrangements . Okay ?
- Come - Mr. Detective ...
Listen , had you ever been in jail ?
- No ... I haven 't been to jail . - But you will now .
- What 's the matter ? - Nothing . Nothing at all .
Didn 't you take the goats to graze ? They 're bleating with hunger .
If they 're hungry , they 'll go themselves .
They know the grass and the way too
- You 're well , aren 't you , my dear ? - Yes , I am
- Oh Uncle ! - What is it , dear ?
- Oh Uncle ... - Go , my dear
Worried about the goats , but not me !
At my age , I 'm worried only about you . Now go on ...
Come along , Uncle 's darling ... Go straight to the meadow , okay ?
Go on ... Hurry up now
Come on ... You too
Why are you making a fuss now ? Come along now . Come on
Come on ... Please come , sir
You come with me , okay ?
You hunted the address and now you 're asking me if it 's my house ?
- I came here ... - I came here , eh ?
There 's no cure for your illness here
Go to the Manor and you 'll be taken care of very well
Shall I go then ?
Hey !
That 's not the way . It 's the other way
Can 't you see , I 've to go out ? So get aside
Don 't the villagers offer water to the thirsty ones ?
Did I dream that you were thirsty ?
You 're the limit !
God knows where they come from !
Get some more
Isn 't your thirst quenched ?
When alive , the thirst of the Lords of the Manor of this village
was never quenched till today , nor will it ever be
And the whole world knows that 's it 's not your fault , sir
Worshipping beauty is in your blood - Mohan !
My silence will neither change your habits nor your fate
Even then ... That 's Ramlal . Radha 's Uncle
If you 're thinking of abducting Radha , then go ahead and murder
- Mohan ! - But his cough doesn 't get better
and he keeps coughing
- I don 't like the way you talk - To each his own
- Mohan ... - Come Ramlal . Look , who 's here !
The last heir to the Chandangad Estate , Kumar Vijay Singh
Kumar , in my house ? Radha ... where are you ?
Radha , look who 's here ... Come here , my dear .
She 'll meet him some other time , sir
Why did you take the trouble , sir ? You could 've called me at the Manor
I can never forget how much your forefathers have obliged me
How can you ? Well Ramlal , even after the murder of his Uncle
do you still believe that it wasn 't the work of some ghost ?
Mohan , pull my leg all you want . But I 've said it before and
I 'll say it again . Ghosts don 't kill in this manner
I think , it 's a shrewd man posing as a ghost who 's doing it all
But I 've heard that God punishes those who terrorize others .
Right , I 'll go now . You 're staying back ?
Yes
I 'm very glad to know that you don 't believe in ghosts and spirits
If only I would know the secret of the anklets ...
That 's the problem . Nobody knows anything
Tonight I 'll go towards the swamp
You 're repeating the same mistake that your forefathers did
Let alone ... Your family is cursed as it is
Death is inevitable , Uncle . Anyway , we 'll meet again
Why are you sitting in the dark ? Light the lamp , my dear
What are you thinking about ?
Why do the Lords of the Manor go in the swamp to die ?
Why do they go there ... that 's very difficult to tell
A pitch-black night ... 9 : 30 p.m. Jingle of the anklets ...
What link does that sound have with the death of the Landlords
is very hard to tell
Uncle , what if Kumar doesn 't venture near that swamp ?
I tried to stop him but did he listen ?
My dear , that 's the curse on these Lords of the Manor
Nobody can help them
" Somewhere there burns a lamp , elsewhere a heart "
" Come and take a look O ' beloved ... "
" Which is your destination ? "
" Somewhere there burns a lamp , elsewhere a heart "
" My song is the cry from my heart "
" Wherever I am , therein lies your love "
" My heart is your merriment "
" Come and take a look O ' beloved ... "
" Where are you heading ? "
" Somewhere there burns a lamp , elsewhere , a heart "
No , I can 't do this . What if you get arrested again ?
I 'll have to go to jail again . But first I 'll have to finish
that job for which I had to escape from jail . Tonight you ...
Dr. Pandey ?
First , it was the anklets jingle that pulled your forefather
to the swamp . Now , there 's a song added !
What are you doing here so late at night ?
I ... I had been to see a patient
The climate of this village is so good that nobody falls sick and dies
But gets murdered
I 'll leave
No , doctor ... no
If I want , I can knock you out within 5 minutes
See this injection ? It can kill a person in a jiffy
No , doctor ... no !
Brace yourself now
Finish , eh ?
My God !
Who 's there ? Who is it ?
I 'm detective Gopichand
- Detective ? - Is that man dead ?
You can go now
- Yes ? - Wait a minute
Well doc , if a man dies ... I mean if he 's murdered ...
- Then ... - Then ?
Then , you 'll have to give his death certificate ...
I mean , a doctor will have to give it , right ?
- If need be ... - Then , give me one in advance please
Don 't worry . If such an opportunity arises
I 'll be very happy to do this for you
I 'm a doctor . I can do as I wish
" I can do as I wish " , eh ?
Look . If you 're a doctor , I 'm a detective too
I too have proofs that can help me catch the killer in a jiffy
- Really ? - Police means trouble !
- What are you getting at ? - That 's what I 'm trying to tell
The reward to catch the killer is Rs . 10,000 / - , right ?
Yes - Good .
And here there 's just one buggy which belongs to you . Right ?
Yes - Very good
- So ? - If you give me just 5,000 / ...
I 'll seal my lips forever
And I 'll scoot from this place now this very minute , if you wish
You really are a clever detective
You understand , eh ? Well , how about the cash ?
- Bahadur ! - Does he keep the cash ?
- Bahadur ! - Shall I make him lie
on the table too ? Come , sir
Is this man crazy ? Go and get some water !
Okay then , I 'll go now . I 've the proof but not the witness
That 's why I wanted to make a deal at Rs . 5,000 / -
Even Rs . 2,000 / - Would have done
After having turned every stone at the site of the murder
it was found that there was an underground tunnel there
Whoever you are , come out
- Here I am . - You ? Here ?
This is the only place here where a man can spend some time in peace
You chose a good spot but even then , let 's go
Why ? Scared of the murderer , eh ?
- Scared of death - O my God !
Come on ... come on
Dear Lord ... What a place !
O ' Lord ! Another snake , sir
- So what ? - So what , eh ?
You scared me back there
Can 't you see ? It 's a python
I know
What 's this ?
- A tunnel beneath the trees - Yes
Yes ?
It 's something to think over
- Then , you think it over - Oh ? I don 't understand any of this
- Greetings , Mr. Gopichand - Greetings ...
Greetings , I said , Mr. Gopichand
Oh , Radha ... I thought , it was the ghost
I 've really lost my marbles after coming here
Even a girl sitting on a tree seems like a ghost to me
Do you know ? There 's a tunnel near the site of the crimes
- I know . - You know ?
You 're excited as though you 've caught the killer !
This is a village . Nothing can be hidden here
- You mean , everybody knows it ? - Yes . And do you know ...
- Yes ? - All the villages around here
know it too ! - Really ?
Then why am I getting so upset ? - For nothing
Had the murderer been a human I 'd have caught him within 24 hours
- You , sir ? - Yes , me
Unbelievable !
Honestly , this is not the work of a human , but a spirit
And to trap a spirit , one needs a sorcerer
We don 't need bullets , we need " mantras "
Then , what are you doing here ?
I 'll go away right now , but ... what about my return fare ?
I tell you , whenever I think of leaving , the villagers get emotional
They sob and say , Detective sir , if you leave
will that ghost spare us ? You 're the only one it 's scared of
Then I also stay back thinking if I really leave
what 'll happen to these folks and Kumar too !
That 's why ... Eh ? She has gone !
I 'm trying to finish your unfinished diary , Uncle
But I don 't know whether I 'll be able to do so
Chandangad is still a puzzle , even today
The same wailing , the jingle of anklets ...
The same haunting silence , and fear ...
Whom do I suspect ? The more I try to solve it , the harder it gets
The sound of that plaintive song at night
It 's like a cry of somebody 's unfulfilled love
" Somewhere a lamp burns , elsewhere , a heart "
" Just come and see O ' beloved ... what 's your destiny "
" Somewhere a lamp burns , elsewhere a heart "
" My song is a cry from my heart "
" Wherever I am there lies your love "
" My heart is your merriment . Come and see , O ' beloved "
" Where lies your destiny ? "
" Somewhere a lamp burns , elsewhere a heart "
" I am neither a dream nor a mystery "
" But a plaintive cry "
" Please don 't be late , come and meet me "
" Come and see , my beloved ... "
" What 's your destiny "
" Somewhere a lamp burns , elsewhere a heart "
" There are many here who are against love "
" Take care with whom you see eye to eye "
" The killer is in various forms "
What I took to be a call of death
may be it 's a cry for love
Whether it 's a cry for death or love , we die for both
But the point is , if it 's a ghost calling out ...
Why didn 't it call you to the site of the murder ?
And if it 's for love , then why not come face to face ?
- Something 's fishy . - Be patient .
When the times comes you 'll come to know too
Laxman !
He has to be the same Laxman who broke from the jail . Right !
I see ... So Laxman is the murderer
But who is he signaling to ? I 'll catch him right now
Eh ? Laxman 's disappeared !
My God ...
Kumar sir ... Mr. Kumar ...
Coffee , sir
Where 's my black coat ? My overcoat is missing too
Mr. Kumar , I 've something very urgent to say to you
- I know who the murderer is . - You do ?
Yes
How could he escape my beady eye ?
- Who is he ? - The one whom I always suspected .
- Laxman . - Coffee .
Coffee , Master .
What 's the matter ? You 're sweating profusely .
So did my father .
I just met Kumar little while ago .
He 's from such an aristocratic family , but so simple .
Shall I go there , too ?
May I ?
Kumar said you had a fight with him ?
I just had a spat with him . Had you been there ...
you would 've examined his head . He panicked the goats with his gun
And when I asked him about it , he pretended to be deaf-dumb
I took a pitcher full of water and he drank it all . So simple !
That 's why he has come here to die ! No matter what you say .
Look Uncle , if I meet him I 'll give him such a sermon
that he 'll run away from this village forever !
" Tell your eyes that they may not miss the target "
" Tell your eyes ... "
" When every movement of yours is so killing ... "
" Tell your eyes that they may not miss the target "
" Tell your eyes ... "
" Shall I call you a killer ? Or should I call you beloved ? "
" I am really in a fix as what to call you "
" It 's for you to decide . You can kill anybody you like "
" But if you want to heed me , then don 't play such games "
" This naughtiness of yours may really take someone 's life "
" Tell your eyes that they may miss the target "
" Tell your eyes ... "
" You are looking so naive "
" lt 'll be a lie to call you cruel "
" This simplicity , this naughtiness , this mischief ... "
" Why do you need swords , arrows and daggers to kill ? "
" One long look at you and the guy will drop dead anyway "
" Tell your eyes that they may not miss the target "
" Tell your eyes ... "
" Why get so angry with me ? There are others who admire you too "
" Get angry with the spring which is mirrored in your eyes "
" Get angry with the breeze which entangles in your hair "
" Let there be nobody who would steal your heart "
" Tell your eyes that they may not miss the target "
" Tell your eyes ... "
" When there is so much fun in your every movement , so killing "
" Tell your eyes that they may not miss the target "
" Tell your eyes ... "
Why are you here ? If I get caught I 'll not only lose the job
but go to jail too .
Yes , yes . It will be done Everything will be done tonight
- Keep an eye on that spy . - Okay , I will
I 'll keep an eye , but now you go away from here . Go
There ! Look at that , Kumar sir
I 'm going towards the swamp . You keep an eye on Laxman
Tonight is the last night
The body is gone !
No I won 't believe this . Kumar can 't die
It can 't be possible , I won 't believe it
It can never be . I 'll never believe it
Someone has died today , tomorrow it will be somebody else
Mr. Kumar , you 're still alive ? - Looks like it . Why ?
I thought something else . Well , anyway ...
Tell me , why don 't you talk ?
A man from the village is murdered and you refuse to identify him
Look again . Turn him over
Sir , we 've never seen this man
Okay , cover him up
- Same old reply . - Whose ?
Who else ? Mr. Kumar
I told him so many times ... - He won 't leave the village , will he ?
That 's what hurts me
An incarnation of this era ! He 'll become a martyr now .
He 'll fly the Royal Standard high . - It was high , my dear
His father respected me so much . He called me Civil surgeon
Do you know , my dear ? He gave me this suit
One day he suddenly died and his younger brother took the title
And ever since then , their family is cursed
Uncle , suppose we go to the swamp before 9 : 30 p . M
and save Kumar ?
Nothing could be better
- Kumar , sir ... - Yes ?
There 's no doubt that Laxman stole your coat and gave it
to that swamp-thief ! - That I can 't say
But there 's no doubt that because he wore my clothes ...
Wait
You mean , the killer took him to be you , and killed him by mistake !
Thank God you don 't venture towards the swamp at night
When the murder took place I was very much in the swamp !
Yes , but before the murder someone pushed me and I fell down
Pushed you , eh ? Then it must be a ghost
One who has nobody to weep over his death ...
Why did you get so upset over his death ?
How was I to know , you didn 't die ?
Had I died would you have been happy ?
What ?
I just wish that God grants me a very long life and ...
I can watch you like this forever
But I 'm scared of the devil .
Whether a coward lives or dies , it 's one and the same thing
If a man shows courage he not only finds a way to stay alive ...
But a reason too !
" Get angry with the spring that is mirrored in your eyes "
" Get angry with the breeze that entangles in your hair "
" Let no man ever steal your heart "
" A man who has nobody to weep over his death ... "
" Why should his death upset you so much ? "
" I wish , God grants me a long life and I ... "
" And I can watch you like this forever "
Got startled by your own footfalls ?
You 've forgotten the sound of your own footfalls ?
Yes
Get lost ! Nice advice you gave me
I see him before my eyes all day and you ask me to forget him !
Now you tell me , is it so easy to forget ?
" Don 't make me so restless and go away "
" For my sake , please come back "
" Those black clouds there , may not steal the thickness of your hair "
" And the mischievous lightning may not steal your style "
" Don 't take another step on your own ... "
" For my sake , please come back "
" Don 't make me restless and go away "
" Those rose laden branches may not reach out to kiss your feet "
" There are footloose bees too here . One of them may not make you his "
" Beware of lusty gazes ... for my sake , please come to me "
" Don 't make me uneasy and go ... for my sake , please come to me "
" The paths of life are very strange . Don 't walk them in this way "
" Madam , it 's for your own good . Find yourself a companion "
" Don 't smile to yourself like this . For my sake please come back "
" Don 't make me restless and go away . For my sake , please come back "
Welcome . Anything new ?
Latest is that your medicine has brought me much relief .
Before I used to tire very easily . Now I can walk for miles comfortably .
I 'm making this medicine for you only
If you control your drinking , you 'll soon start running
The medicine seems very potent . It has hurt your finger too
Poison has to be treated with poison !
The villagers say that you 're getting Radha married to Kumar for money
It 's become a habit with them to gossip
My words exactly
If you say so , with this new medicine ...
I 'll also think of changing my habits too
- When will I get the medicine ? - I 'll send it across when ready
Right
Did you hear ? People say your curse is ending the ruling dynasty
But I 'll save it 's last heir with your blessings
Heed me and stop playing these dangerous games with life
You want human sacrifice ? Then take my life and save Kumar
I 'm not begging . But you will lose against my prayers
Still I plead ... Give me courage and keep Kumar
Answer me , O ' Lord . Answer me
Give Kumar a long life . Please Lord
Answer my prayers O ' Lord . Do something
Radha ! You ?
You 're here so late in the night ? Alone ...
Why , Radha ? What will people say ?
This is the blessing from the Lord for your long life
Please take it .
My life ?
Why not ? Come with me . Come on
All of them did so much for this village , that they were revered
And then ...
This painting here
My Grandpa 's . Because of his ill-deeds , my family was cursed .
My father ... he was murdered
My uncle ... he was killed too
Radha ... I may be knowing what 's in your mind
And I think about it all the time
But even then I can do nothing . You don 't know
how helpless I am . How hopelessly helpless
See this empty space Radha
One of these days my portrait will be hanging there !
Kumar !
You ... why do you think in this way ?
My thinking or not thinking will hardly make a difference
A man was killed because he wore my clothes ...
How long will I survive the curse on my family ?
Why don 't you leave this wretched estate ?
My leaving the estate will not end the curse
Wonder which unhappy woman 's wail it is
If a woman 's wail has so much power that she destroy a dynasty
Then a woman 's love is as powerful to smother that wail itself !
Radha !
Radha , if you 've so much confidence in your love then it 'll be as you say
Come , let 's go
Radha , in the Manor at night ? All alone ?
Uncle ... Uncle ...
Dear Uncle ... You 're great !
Uncle ... Why don 't you say something ?
You haven 't even lit a lamp . Sitting in the dark , are you ?
Uncle ...
Tears in your eyes ?
Uncle ... What 's happened to you ?
Uncle , tell me . Please , Uncle
You won 't tell me , eh ?
Wiping tears will not wipe away the stigma
Stigma ?
Why are you talking like this today ?
One small excuse is enough to sling mud at a poor man 's respect
And you 've given them such a big chance , Radha
You went to the Manor at night , all alone ?
Do you realize what you 've done ?
You 've trampled your family 's respect with your own feet !
Uncle ! I just went ...
A pebble can 't replace a gem . It never has , it never will
You forgot your own worth and went to the Manor
Won 't the people tease us now ? - Uncle , please
How will I face them ?
You 've ruined me completely
Uncle , I swear on your head , I 've not sinned
I 've not done anything to be ashamed of
I have that much faith in you , dear
Else instead of me , you 'd have found my corpse here !
Uncle !
If you really care for me then stop seeing Kumar completely
Uncle ! Don 't say that
Okay . You decide for yourself . Either Kumar or my life
O , Uncle !
First I thought , I 'd catch the murderer
But now I have no hopes at all
If you know any small detail about the killer , then ...
- What killer are you talking about ? - What ?
- You mean there are many here ? - I don 't know about others
- But I am one murderer ! - You ?
Yes
I barred Radha from meeting Kumar , so she has stopped eating
Now tell me , how long will she survive without food ?
2-4 days
If she dies within 2-4 days , won 't I be charged with murder ?
Of course you will be ! Without any doubt . I 'll go now
- I 'm going back ... - You 're not going . You 're coming
I 've come to tell you that this time I 'm really going
Okay
You don 't think that I 'm going in the next room , do you ?
No
No . But I also know that you can 't go back to the city
- Why ? - Because you still haven 't
got the reward money !
That 's true . But tell me , when there are murderers by the dozen ...
- What can I do on my own ? - But I 'm with you
Do you think your name isn 't on the list of murderers ?
If that girl dies , you 'll be regarded as the murderer
- Which girl ? - Radha , whom you 've trapped
in a web of love .
The poor girl 's starving for days now
Do you think , she will live ?
" O love , you had no business to come in my life "
" Before you came , there wasn 't any mention of grief in my life ... "
" Don 't know , why I 've everything against the world today "
" Before this , nobody was guilty of anything "
" O love , you had no business to enter my life "
" I was destined to cry "
" And there was no love in my lot "
" O love , you had no business to come in my life "
" O giver of life , you only gave me love "
" Wasn 't I at peace before being struck by love ? "
" O love , you had no right to enter my life "
Radha ...
Radha ... What 's wrong with you ?
Tell me the truth , Radha . What 's the matter ?
Uncle doesn 't want us to meet each other
You got so upset over such a small thing ?
- Come on , get up . - Uncle will kill himself
If we let him die for our love , then love will be slandered forever
If it 's true love , then it forces even the Almighty to bow to it
And Uncle is but a man . No Radha . This cannot be
- I won 't let you do this . - I don 't understand
I don 't know what to do ? Please leave me alone
- I 'll see you later . - And I 'll wait for you
Come , my dear
Will you say something or just go on crying like this ?
Tell me , my dear . What do you want from me ?
Don 't you know , your happiness , peace of mind , is my life 's wish
O ' Uncle ...
Okay my dear , you can be sure that I 've taken my decision back
No , I don 't want my happiness at the cost of yours
- I know , you don 't really wish it . - I do my dear . Honestly
What could give me more joy than Kumar accepting you ?
Uncle ! O ' Uncle ...
Who knows God 's will ?
It could be that , if your love is true
the curse on the landlord 's of Chandangad may end forever
Uncle ... I always knew that you 're not hard hearted
In this whole world you love only me , don 't you ?
Get lost !
I must also meet Kumar now , mustn 't I ?
Okay , ask him to meet me in the temple near the swamp
so that I can talk things over with him
No ... - Go on
Don 't waste time , my dear . - I won 't go
So ! Tonight Kumar will be at the temple near the swamp
Maybe , tonight is my night
- Ramdhin ! - Sir !
Before our secret gets out ...
We must change the plans
Radha !
No , nothing very special . Just a small party at my place
If you can attend the party , I 'll consider myself very fortunate
At night ? Okay , I 'll come . - Thank you very much
Greetings , Mr. Ramlal - Greetings , Mr. Gopichand
Collecting shoots and roots are you ?
- Yes . - I see .
Didn 't you ask me about the killer that day ?
I won 't now . Ever !
If you won 't tell anyone , shall I tell you something ?
Why should I tell anyone anything ? That day Kumar asked me
how was Radha , but I hardly told him that she was refusing to eat !
- Mr. Gopichand ... - Yes ?
I 've noticed that a man hides behind that hill all day
And then at night he 's wandering about in the swamp
Wanders about , eh ? Then he must be the murderer
I 'll go and set him straight right this minute !
Hands up !
Gopichand ? - Come along , Mr. Murderer
Where , the police station ? - No , to the Taj Mahal at Agra !
Come along
Inspector ... I 've caught the murderer
Hey you , lock him up ! Come on , hurry up
Inspector ...
- What 's the matter ? - Ask me , what 's not the matter !
- I 've caught the murderer - You ?
Yes ! - Where is he ?
There he is !
- Inspector ... - Yes sir ?
Did you post the letter I sent you ?
Yes sir
Right . Mr. Gopichand , sit down
Have I come to the wrong place ? Is this a police station or ...
- There goes my reward money . - Gopichand ...
You are interested in the reward money , eh ?
I was , but not anymore !
Inspector ... the D.S.P. Has called me to the city at once
I 'll have to go by the first train . But tonight ...
Be alert , Inspector
You can also try your luck
Inspector ...
Police detective , Mr. Tripathi
I don 't believe it . It can 't be
Shout ! Shout all you want and ruin everything !
- Say what you want . - Silence ! I 'll kill you !
- Then , kill me ! - Laxman !
No , I won 't . I won 't ... I won 't believe it
Laxman , who 's this girl ?
Murdered . The man who was killed that night was her husband
- I asked you , who this girl is . - Sister . My sister
He was a jail-breaker . My brother-in-law
I didn 't keep him in the Manor
He lived in the swamp . My sis asked me to signal him with a lantern
So that she could take food to him when it was safe
I used to tell her to make him go somewhere very far
- But she used to cry . - And you shut her mouth every night
So that I won 't hear her crying . - Yes
- Then ? - I stole ...
I only stole your black coat
He agreed . My brother-in-law agreed to go away from here
And then ...
You kept your sister here without permission because you love her
A sister who loves her husband so much that she refuses
to accept his death . You just told her that her husband is dead ?
Why didn 't you let her see with her own eyes that she was a widow ?
She has gone mad . The moment she heard of her husband 's death ...
- She became mad . - I won 't believe it
It 's the Lords of the Manor that are cursed , not my husband
He can 't die ! He can never die !
- You 'll have to take care now - So what ?
Thanks . When will the doc come ? - Should be here soon
I 'm sorry , Kumar . I had to see a patient
But unfortunately , I couldn 't save him
Please sit down . I 'll just come
- Greetings , doctor - Greetings
Doctor , I lost this round
" Somewhere there burns a lamp , elsewhere a heart "
" Come and see dear beloved ...
" what you 're destined for "
" Somewhere there burns a lamp , elsewhere a heart "
" I 'm neither a dream nor am I a mystery "
" But just a plaintive cry ... "
" Please don 't be late in coming "
" Come and see dear beloved , what you 're destined for "
" Somewhere there burns a lamp , elsewhere a heart "
- Did you see Kumar ? - Yes
- He went straight to the swamp . - To the swamp . All alone !
- Radha ! - You !
Had you not deceived me today , I 'd have ...
I see
By lying about fixing the marriage you had come to kill Kumar ...
You wanted to widow me before I even became a bride ?
- But why ? - Why ?
To quench his lust , Kumar 's grandpa had kidnapped my daughter Champa
on her wedding night . And Radha
when I went to the Manor , to beg for your cousin 's honor ...
But for one man 's crime you wanted to finish off the whole lineage ?
That night , after regaining my senses , when I reached home ...
It would 've been better had you let me die that day too
At least I wouldn 't be standing here like this in front of you today !
Tell me , where Kumar is . I beg you !
Beg ?
Not for me , but your cousin . Her soul 's disturbed . Where 's Kumar ?
If this is how she 'll find peace , then sacrifice me , Uncle !
Follow him ! Why did you come here ?
- What more can a girl do ? - But I had forbidden you
Uncle had asked me to bring Kumar in the temple near here
- To solve the problem ... - Where 's Kumar now ?
Follow him
Kumar 's trapped in the tunnel - What !
Uncle ... O , Uncle
Who is it ? Open the door
Open the door , I say !
Kumar
- So you 're here , eh ? - You ?
May be God wishes it that I fulfill my vow
- You ? - Yes , me . I 'm the murderer
It was me who for the past 20 years tied bells on a cat 's feet
and let it roam in the swamp
And hearing the sound of those bells ... you dare !
May be Kumar was shot by the murderer
There must be a way here somewhere . Search
Surround the place . Go that way
Hands up !
Trapped at last ! Ramlal , I always suspected that
some shrewd man is behind this conspiracy
Inspector , arrest him
There 's no way out here . - This is a dead end too , sir
Then , where 's he gone ?
Don 't let him escape
Here 's the one with bells on her feet !
Surrender yourself to the police
You can 't get away from this swamp
Don 't try to escape , Ramlal
This is my final warning
Don 't try to run away
Ramlal , don 't try to run away . Come down and surrender yourself
Inspector ... I got my punishment for the crimes I committed
And Kumar ... Radha 's love for you has defended me today
Radha ... Please forgive me , my dear
I 'm very sorry , Dr. Pandey . I always suspected you
Anybody else in your place would 've suspected Dr. Pandey too
He always used to roam in the swamp to catch the killer
No . Ramlal killing again and again . That haunting song at night ...
Radha used to sing the song . To lure Kumar away from the swamp
And Ramlal killed in revenge
- Revenge ? - This Ramlal is in fact , Radheshyam
Whose daughter was abducted by the then Lord of the Manor
That 's it ! Crime never pays
" Somewhere there burns a lamp , elsewhere , a heart "
" Come take a look my beloved "
" What is your destination ? "
" Somewhere there burns a lamp , elsewhere , a heart "